Guide to the Whitman College Archives Walla Walla Vertical Files Collection approximately 1900-2005
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
- County of Walla Walla: Wild Horse Co
- County of Walla Walla: Walla Walla River
- Crime: crime misc.
- Crime: crimes- general
- Crime: assault, kidnapping 1980
- Crime: assaults including rape
- Crime: break-ins, disturbances, prowlers
- Crime: break-ins
- Crime: break-ins, burglaries, thefts
- Crime: Crime check Committee
- Crime: Forgery, fraud, gambling, counterterfeiting 1980
- Crime: DWI
- Crime: Murder
- Crime: Murder, suicide, shooting, stabbing (2 folders)
- Crime: Murder Trials
- Crime: Murder Trial Crudup case
- Crime: Murder Trial Messinger case
- Crime: narcotics
- Crime: Narcotics, drug, theft 1981
- Crime: robberies
- Crime: stabbings
- Crime: theft
- Crime: Juvenile Justice
- Culture: Cultural activities
- Culture: culture
- Culture: Latino Culture
- Day Care: Day Care centers
- Day Care: Day care / preschool
- Eastern Lillies: Earthquakes (2 folders)
- Eastern Lillies: Emergency Services 911 Magazine
- Eastern Lillies: Employment / Unemployment
- Fairs: McFaden and Gorman 1903 WW County Fair Association 2 stock shares certificate
- Fairs: S. E. W. articles
- Fairs: Southeastern Washington Fairgrounds
- Fairs: Fruit Fair
- Fairs: Frontier Days
- Fires: Walla Walla fires
- Fires: fire districts
- Fires: City Fire department (4 folders)
- Fires: fires (2 folders)
- Fires: Fires 1978-1979
- Fires: Fires 1980
- Fires: Fires 1990s
- Fires: Floods Walla Walla area
- Fires: Fire - Walla Walla country club
- Fires: Fire Department
- Fires: Parker Barrett 1901-1921 receipts and bills
- Fires: Tax receipts of Walla Walla Co.
- Fires: Tax receipt 1862
- Fraternal Organizations: Records, receipts, other papers, 1869-1934.
- Fraternal Organizations: Men and Religion Forward Movement Conference program Feb. 23, 1912 at Odd Fellows Temple.
- Forestry Service: Forestry and related industry (2 folders)
- Forestry Service: forestry service
- Forestry Service: U.S. Forest Service
- Fort Walla Walla: V. A. Hospital
- Fort Walla Walla: Fort WW amphitheatre other than Trails West
- Gardening
- Health Services: Alcohol
- Health Services: Alcohol council and other groups (4 files)
- Health Services: Alcoholism
- Health Services: County Alcoholism administrative board
- Health Services: City-county ambulance and paramedic (5 files)
- Health Services: Blood donation
- Health Services: American Cancer Society
- Health Services: Clinics
- Health Services: City-county health department
- Health Services: misc/general
- Health Services: Catholic Children and Family Service
- Health Services: Child abuse and neglect
- Health Services: food banks
- Health Services: grief busters
- Health Services: Heart Fund
- Health Services: Health, Education, Welfare (HEW)
- Health Services: Hospice
- Health Services: Hospital
- Health Services: Lillie Rice Center
- Health Services: March of Dimes
- Health Services: Meals on Wheels
- Health Services: Mental Health Center
- Health Services: Nursing homes
- Health Services: Oddfellows
- Health Services: Red Cross
- Health Services: Salvation Army
- Health Services: United Way
- Health Services: Walla Walla Clinic
- History: City of Walla Walla History
- History: Walla Walla History- News Clippings and Publications
- History: Walla Walla History (notes taken by Reynolds on reminiscenses of Clark)
- History: Lawrence L. Dodd research
- History: Blue Mountain Ramblings Vance Orchard
- History: Blue Mountains (2 files)
- History: misc/general
- History: books, articles
- History: businesses
- History: Columbia High School at Two Rivers
- History: Council Grove
- History: Documents
- History: Downtown Walla Walla and Main Street
- History: History fairs
- History: "Firsts in Walla Walla"
- History: Fort Bennett
- History: Gardena Community Club
- History: Historical Sites of Walla Walla
- History: Immigration/Immigrant Labor
- History: Indians
- History: Italian Heritage
- History: Klicker Stories (written by Don Klicker)
- History: Legends
- History: Mining and the development of Walla Walla
- History: Museums
- History: Music
- History: Naming / Name of Walla Walla
- History: "On This Date"
- History: People, personalities, personal narratives
- History: Prostitution
- History: "Remember When…"
- History: "Remember" Vance Orchard
- History: roads, trails
- History: Russell Creek area
- History: citizens committee
- History: Sasauma Japan
- History: Sister city (2 files)
- History: sports
- History: "Today's Little Journey"
- History: Transportation
- History: "Twice Told in Walla Walla"
- History: Winters in Walla Walla
- Homes: misc/general
- Homes: Abbott House
- Homes: Allen House
- Homes: Anderson
- Homes: Bleakney House
- Homes: Board
- Homes: Brown House
- Homes: Bruce Mansion
- Homes: Buttler House
- Homes: Cabins
- Homes: Cornwell
- Homes: Coyle Homestead
- Homes: Destruction of Homes
- Homes: Doty's dream house
- Homes: Drake House
- Homes: Drumheller Home
- Homes: Elliott House
- Homes: George Evans House
- Homes: Green Gables Inn
- Homes: Hood Home
- Homes: Hungate home
- Homes: Isaac's Place
- Homes: Kibler Home
- Homes: Moore House
- Homes: McCaw Housing Project
- Homes: Nelms House
- Homes: Odd Fellows Home
- Homes: Ranson Clark Cabin
- Homes: Real Estate Showcase
- Homes: Rees
- Homes: Rees Mansion Inn
- Homes: J. H. Stahl House
- Homes: P. H. Linkton Cabin
- Homes: Retirement homes
- Homes: Ritz House
- Homes: Ed F. Seil House
- Homes: Snyder HouseStahl Home
- Homes: Stubblefield Home
- Homes: Suttner Home
- Homes: Waldheim Baumeister House
- Homes: Ward House
- Housing: Blue Mountain Boys' Ranch
- Housing: Homeless Solutions (Walla Walla)
- Housing: Housing in Walla Walla
- Housing: House Serves for Handicaps
- Housing: housing authorities
- Housing: HUD
- Housing: HUD and NHIP 1980\
- Housing: Low - Income Housing
- Housing: Housing Authority
- Housing: labor camp
- Human Interest: General
- Human Interest: Leadership Walla Walla
- Libraries: Walla Walla City Libraries
- Malls: Blue Mt. Mall
- Malls: Eastgate Mall
- Malls: Mini Mall
- Maps: Walla Walla 1961
- Maps: Maps of city
- Maps: McCool Catholic Cemetery
- Mill Creek: watershed
- Mill Creek: Mill Creek and Koos Koos Kie
- National Guard
- Newspapers: General
- Newspapers: Union Bulletin
- Newspapers: U.B. Athlete of the week
- Newspapers: Walla Walla Statesman
- Newspapers: Walla Walla Union
- Northwest Miscellaneous: General
- Northwest Miscellaneous: Walla Walla City Transportation
- Northwest Miscellaneous: Indians
- Northwest Miscellaneous: Fort Simcoe
- Northwest Miscellaneous: Palouse Falls
- Northwest Miscellaneous: Snake River
- Northwest Miscellaneous: Walla Walla River
- Northwest Miscellaneous: Wallula
- Organizations: Walla Walla County Bar Association minute book 1902-1913
- Organizations: Walla Walla Dental Society annual meeting photograph 1983
- Organizations: Dentists Walla Walla group photo 1983
- Organizations: Dentist Fee Schedule 1983
- Organizations: Walla Walla County Bar Association Records. schedule of minimum fees
- Organizations: Walla Walla Dentists' correspondence
- Organizations:
- Organizations: Downtown Walla Walla Foundation
- Organizations: Civilian Conservation Corps Camp in WW Records. Photogrpahs, negatives, and articles
- Organizations: Walla Walla Association for the Advancement of Science Records, 1878 booklet: articles of incorporation (Donated by Henrietta Baker Kennedy)
- Organizations: Astronomical Station 1878 report (copy)
- Organizations: Center for Sharing
- Organizations: Organizations misc.
- Organizations: Walla Walla Gardner's Association
- Organizations: Municipal League of WW constitution, articles of incorporation 1894 (3 folders)
- Organizations: misc/general
- Organizations: Altrusa
- Organizations: American Red Cross
- Organizations: Audobon Society
- Organizations: Blue Mountain Action Council (4 folders)
- Organizations: Blue Mountain Area Foundation
- Organizations: Blue Mountain Art Alliance
- Organizations: Blue Moutain Boys Ranch
- Organizations: Blue Mt. Comprehensive Health Planning Council
- Organizations: Blue Mt. Riders
- Organizations: Country Club
- Organizations: Business Mens Services Bureau
- Organizations: Camera Club
- Organizations: Camp Farthest Out
- Organizations: Camp Fire
- Organizations: Center for sharing
- Organizations: Children's Home Society (2 folders)
- Organizations: Civil Air Patrol
- Organizations: clubs: misc
- Organizations: Christian Aid Center
- Organizations: Lodges / clubs
- Organizations: Communitee Connection
- Organizations: Cyclamates
- Organizations: Camp Wooten
- Organizations: Coalition for Peace
- Organizations: Eagles
- Organizations: Esperanto Society
- Organizations: Exchange Club
- Organizations: 59'ers
- Organizations: 4 - H (3 folders)
- Organizations: Garden Club
- Organizations: GOTR Campground
- Organizations: Historical Architecture
- Organizations: Horse Club
- Organizations: Human Relations League
- Organizations: Jaycees of Walla Walla
- Organizations: Jesus People
- Organizations: Kiwanis Club
- Organizations: Knights of Columbus
- Organizations: Main Street Foundation
- Organizations: Masons
- Organizations: Gay Ninety Revue
- Organizations: Pythian Sisiters
- Organizations: Rose Society
- Organizations: Rotary Club
- Organizations: Senior Citizens Center
- Organizations: History Society
- Organizations: Scouts
- Organizations: Sierra Club
- Organizations: Society of Emissaries
- Organizations: Sweet Adelines
- Organizations: United Way
- Organizations: Teenagers
- Organizations: Three Knights Chess Club
- Organizations: Toastmasters
- Organizations: Vancycle Ridge Wind Energy Project
- Organizations: Veterans Org
- Organizations: Country Club
- Organizations: Camp of Gideons International
- Organizations: Golf Club
- Organizations: Washington Citizens for Fairness
- Organizations: Women and Family Center
- Organizations: Women's Gold Assoc
- Organizations: Wheat Growers Assoc
- Organizations: Bicentennial Celebration
- Pageants: Miss Walla Walla Pageant
- Pageants: Pioneer Pageant
- Parks: misc / general (2 folders)
- Parks: Walla Walla Parks (13 folders): Green park, Jefferson park, Rooks Park, Trailhead park, Umatilla National Forest, Wildwood Park, Pioneer park, Heriscape park ("Parks, misc. general") file contains Olmsted documents)
- Parks: regional planning commission
- Parks: Youth Enterprise Center
- Parks: county park board (2 folders)
- Parks: parks and recreation dept. (4 folders)
- Parks: Walla Walla Trees Video
- Parks: Fort Walla Walla
- Parks: City parks and recreations dept.
- People: Graham, Melvina
- People: McKay, Mabelle Eastman
- People: Estes Family
- People: Meyer-Lucinger family
- People: Arnold, James
- People: Beeman, Rufus and Caroline
- People: Babcock, Jonothan
- People: Teel Family
- People: Paine, Francis Warren
- People: Burnap Family
- People: Singleton Genealogy
- People: Philip Adam Ruppert
- People: Horace and Olive Hart
- People: Caple Family Genealogy
- People: Henry B. Day Family
- People: Rosencrances by Ted Van Arsdol
- People: Jason Coward Chastain and family
- People: Walla Walla people (6 folders): appointments, honors bestowed upon, illegal aliens, medical personel, obituaries, working women
- People: Russian Immigrants
- People: Vietnam Refugee in Walla Walla
- Police: city police (6 folders)
- Politics: misc/general
- Politics: 1941
- Politics: 1972
- Politics: 1977
- Politics: 1978
- Politics: 1979
- Politics: 1981
- Politics: 1982
- Politics: 1984
- Politics: 1985
- Politics: 1986
- Politics: 1987
- Politics: 1994
- Politics: 1995
- Politics: Democrats (2 files)
- Politics: Organizations and candidates before 1973
- Politics: 1922 special election poll book
- Politics: Protests
- Politics: Republicans
- Politics: Walla Walla County
- Politics: Politics: misc/general
- Politics: Politics election (10 folders)1941-1986
- Politics: Protests
- Politics: recycling
- Politics: Special Election Poll Book. College Precinct. Walla Walla
- Postal Service: Postal: misc/general
- Postal Service: Postal: postmen postmasters
- Postal Service: post offices
- Rivers: General
- Religion: 1981--Churches and Religion
- Religion: Baha'I faith
- Religion: Churches (2 files)
- Schools, primary and secondary: Assumption Elementary
- Schools, primary and secondary: Baker Elementary
- Schools, primary and secondary: Berney Elementary
- Schools, primary and secondary: Blue Ridge Elementary
- Schools, primary and secondary: Walla Walla School Board (5 files)
- Schools, primary and secondary: Braden School
- Schools, primary and secondary: Walla Walla Business School
- Schools, primary and secondary: College Place Schools 1980
- Schools, primary and secondary: Scollege Place Schools (2 files)
- Schools, primary and secondary: College Place School Board (2 fiels)
- Schools, primary and secondary: Community School, inc.
- Schools, primary and secondary: Desales High School
- Schools, primary and secondary: Walla Walla School District 1977
- Schools, primary and secondary: Walla Walla School District 1979
- Schools, primary and secondary: Walla Walla School District 1980
- Schools, primary and secondary: Walla Walla School District 1981
- Schools, primary and secondary: Walla Wall School District (4 files)
- Schools, primary and secondary: Eastside School
- Schools, primary and secondary: Edison Elementary School
- Schools, primary and secondary: Ferndale School
- Schools, primary and secondary: "Focus" newsletter
- Schools, primary and secondary: Freewater School
- Schools, primary and secondary: Fruitvale School
- Schools, primary and secondary: Garrison Elementary
- Schools, primary and secondary: Green Park Elementary
- Schools, primary and secondary: Grove School
- Schools, primary and secondary: Intermediate district
- Schools, primary and secondary: Jeffer School
- Schools, primary and secondary: The Learning Place
- Schools, primary and secondary: Levies
- Schools, primary and secondary: Lewis and Clark High School
- Schools, primary and secondary: Liberty Christian School
- Schools, primary and secondary: Milton School
- Schools, primary and secondary: Pain School (Lincoln)
- Schools, primary and secondary: Pearson's Academy
- Schools, primary and secondary: People
- Schools, primary and secondary: Pettyjohn School
- Schools, primary and secondary: Sharpstein Elementary
- Schools, primary and secondary: St. Patrick's School
- Schools, primary and secondary: St. Paul's School
- Schools, primary and secondary: Superintendents
- Schools, primary and secondary: Walla Walla High School (5 files)
- Schools, primary and secondary: Walla Walla High School Memorabilia
- Schools, primary and secondary: Walla Walla Schools (2 files)
- Schools, primary and secondary: Washington State Historical Schools
- Schools, primary and secondary: Touchet School
- Schools, primary and secondary: Umapine School
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla College prior to 1973
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla College 1978
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla College 1979
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla College 1980
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla College 1981
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla College--general
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla College--people
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College prior to 1973
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College 1975
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College 1976
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College 1977
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College 1978
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College 1979
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College 1980
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College 1981
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College general
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College budget
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College Classes
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College regional bicentennial confrence
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College theatre
- Schools, post-secondary: Walla Walla Community College trustees
- Senior Citizens: Oddfellows home
- Senior Citizens: Senior Citizens: misc/general, programs, plans (6 folders)
- Southeast Washignton Fair: General (4 folders)
- Southeast Washignton Fair: Daughters of the American Revolution
- Sports: Sports: misc/general, baseball, softball, bicycling, borleske stadium, fishing, hunting, football, fun runs, golf, skiing, soccer, Veterans Memorial Athletic Complex (11 folders)
- Streets: names of
- Streets: City streets, roads, and bridges (3 folders)
- Streets: Team Walla Walla
- Streets: Road project
- Transportation: General
- Transportation: Civil Air Patrol of Walla Walla
- Transportation: Airlines 1978 and 1979
- Transportation: Airlines 1980
- Transportation: Airlines (3 files)
- Transportation: Airlines: Cascade, Hughes, Air West
- Transportation: Airlines: West Coast
- Transportation: Airport 1965-1970's
- Transportation: Airports, Airplanes (2 files)
- Transportation: City-County Airport (2 files)
- Transportation: City-County Airport Board (2 files)
- Transportation: Cars
- Transportation: County Roads/Bridges, Engineers
- Transportation: County Streets and Roads (2 files)
- Transportation: Greyhound
- Transportation: Highways (4 files)
- Transportation: Mullan Road
- Transportation: Public Transportation (2 files)
- Transportation: Railways (2 files)
- Transportation: Railway, OW and RandN
- Transportation: Railway, Walla Walla Valley
- Transportation: Roads, Bridges, Traffic Control
- Transportation: Rods, Highways
- Transportation: "Stagecoach Lines Through Walla Walla" by Joye Mott Lucas
- Transportation: Stagecoach
- Transportation: Valley Transit
- Visitors: misc/general
- Visitors: presidential visitors
- Visitors: Tourism
- Visitors: Vigilantes in WW, story is about the winter of 1864; Hangman's Tree. Singleton Homestead. Destroyed by fire. Vigilante. WW Union Bulletin, Aug. 30, 1921 (2 folders)
- Wars: Walla Walla City European War 1914-18 narratives of Walla Walla citizens
- Wars: Pearl Harbor Anniversary Rally program, Dec. 7, 1942, in Walla Walla: war, military
- Wars: Information: 1855 Battle of WW (Frenchtown) article
- Wars: WW1
- Wars: Vietnam
- Wars: Year in review
- Water: Water system Walla Walla
- Water: Environmental Impact Statement for Riovista Burbank Washington: Draft for the Phoenix Irrigation Project, Aug. 1974, Walla Walla Regional Planning Agency. for Walla Walla County area
- Water: Walla Walla Water Department delinquent payment notice, 1920
- Water: Walla Walla Water Works Records. bill, with company rules, 1886
- Water: Walla Walla Water co.